uatoday.tv 2019-06-11

# PRIVACY AND PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION POLICY - UNIAN

**General Provisions**

This <https://www.unian.info/> (hereinafter - the Website) is administered by “UKRAINIAN INDEPENDENT NEWS AND INFORMATION AGENCY”  EDRPOU code 21452108, a legal entity registered and operating in accordance with requirements of current law of Ukraine (hereinafter - the Company).

The Company with great respect treats the confidential (personal) information of each and every person visiting the Website and persons using the services provided by the Website; therefore, the Company is committed to protecting the privacy of personal information (data or a set of data about an individual who is identified or may be specifically identified), thereby creating and providing each user with the most comfortable conditions for using the Website services.

This Privacy and Personal Data Protection Policy (hereinafter – the Policy) establishes the procedure according to which the Company shall process personal data, and also the types of personal data collected, the purposes with which such personal data shall be used, the Company's interaction with third parties, security measures to protect personal data, terms of access to personal data, and also user's contact information for accessing, making changes, blocking or removing his/her personal data and sending any question which you may have about the practice of personal data protection.

 **Personal Data Collection and Use**

Personal data of the Website users shall be owned and administered by “UKRAINIAN INDEPENDENT NEWS AND INFORMATION AGENCY”.

When the user uses the Website services, the Company shall process the user data, in particular:

\- data provided by the user when he/she fills in the registration form, and also while using the services;

\- cookies;

\- ip addresses;

\- options and settings of Internet browsers (User-agent).

The Company shall collect only the personal data (e.g. your first and last name, login and access password, email address, contact telephone number, date of birth, gender, etc.) which you _as the personal data subject_ provide knowingly and willingly with the aim of using the Website services, and thereby, as established by current law, you as the personal data subject give your consent to the processing of your personal data according to the purpose of such processing formulated in this Policy.

When you visit the Website, each login is recorded. Other user traffic data shall not be processed or stored.

Please note: the Company confines itself to collecting the minimum amount of information as may be strictly necessary only to fulfill the personal data subject’s request. In any case, if optional information is requested, the user shall be notified thereof at the time of collection of such information.

The Company shall not collect any information which may be processed only subject to certain statutory limitations, such as information about racial or ethnic origin, political, religious or philosophical beliefs, membership in political parties and trade unions, criminal record, criminal sentences, as well as data relating to health, sex life, biometric or genetic data (article 7 of the Law of Ukraine "On Personal Data Protection").

The Company shall collect the statistical data about visits to the Website. These data may contain the information about connection, traffic, user's browser, and also about the date, time, Internet online time and time of staying on the Website.

 **Personal Data Processing**

The personal data provided shall be processed and stored at the data centers which have the equipment ensuring the operation of the Website services. The personal data provided shall be processed and may be stored in the Personal Database, or in a separate table of the Website Database.

The place where personal data shall be processed and stored shall be at the address: 23 Kyrylivska Str., Kyiv, Ukraine.

 **Purposes of Personal Data Use**

Your personal data shall be used to ensure the provision of the Internet services available on the Website, and also for the purpose of exchanging information/news and maintaining relations in the advertising and communications sector in accordance with and pursuant to the Laws of Ukraine, including but not limited to such Laws as: "On Personal Data Protection", "On Ratification of the Convention for the Protection of Individuals with regard to Automatic Processing of Personal Data and Additional Protocol to the Convention for the Protection of Individuals with regard to Automatic Processing of Personal Data, regarding supervisory authorities and transborder data flows", "On Information", "On Advertising", "On Telecommunications", "On Information Protection in Information and Telecommunication Systems", "On the State Support of Mass Media and Social Protection of Journalists", and also in accordance with the Website Terms of Use and other regulations governing the operation of the Company.

 **Personal Data Storage Term**

Personal data shall be stored for the period not exceeding the time necessary according to the purpose of their processing.

After the personal data subject ceases to be a user of the Website by removing his/her account on the Website, his/her personal data shall also be deleted automatically.

 **Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a text file or files containing small amounts of information which are sent to a web browser and stored on the user's device. Such devices include a computer, a mobile phone or any other device with the help of which the user visits the Website.

Cookies can be permanent (these are called persistent cookies) and they are stored in the computer until the user deletes them, or temporary (these are called session cookies), they are stored only until the browser is closed. Besides, cookies are divided into first-party cookies (they are set directly by the Website visited) and third-party cookies (set by other websites).

 _Important:_

• when you revisit the Website, the cookie data are updated;

• in most cases, the web browser by default allows automatic storage of cookies on the user's device;

• disabling of cookies may result in a restricted access to published materials and/or in inappropriate functioning of the Website services.

The Company takes care of its users and is committed to making your visit to the Website as comfortable as possible; to do this, the Company, using cookies, needs to analyze the behavior, preferences and interests of users. This analysis will help the Company improve the Website interaction experience, determine the most user-friendly interface and Service navigation.

 _According to the classification of the International Chamber of Commerce, the Company will use cookies of the following categories:_

Strictly necessary cookies are essential in order to enable the user to move around the website and use its certain features, such as accessing secure areas, registration and authorization, and searching through the Website. They also remember previous actions of the user when he/she goes back to the previous page in the same session.

Performance cookies collect information about how visitors use a website. These data are stored on the user's device between web browser sessions. As an example of such data, the following metrics may be mentioned: time spent on the Website, most visited pages, understanding which sections and services of the Website are most interesting to a user, or what the efficiency of a certain advertising and/or marketing campaign is etc.

All of the information collected by performance cookies is intended for statistical and analytical tasks. Some cookie data may be shared with third parties who have a permit from the web resource, but exclusively for the purposes described above.

Functionality cookies are used to save the settings or configurations which are stored on the user's device between web browser sessions. As an example of such data, the following metrics may be mentioned: user name, profile photo, information about the comments left, language version of the Website, location, information on whether any information or selected features have already been provided to the user, as well as other features of the Website settings.

These cookies also allow users to watch videos, participate in interactive events (surveys, polls) and interact with social networks.

To make the impressions after visiting the resource more pleasant, these cookies remember the information provided by a user, thus increasing the efficiency of interaction with the Website.

Some cookie data may be shared with third parties who have a permit from the web resource, but exclusively for the purposes described above.

Targeting cookies are used to deliver the content which may be relevant to the user. These data are stored on the user's device between web browser sessions. As an example of such data, the following metrics may be mentioned: tracking of a recommended text, graphics, audio and video to avoid its repeated display to a user, management of targeted advertising, evaluation of advertising campaign efficiency, information about other resources visited by the user while linking to other resources, as well as other features of the Website settings.

The Website may share this information with other parties, including media clients, advertisers, agencies and partners in related businesses to ensure that they provide high-quality targeted advertising.

 _Cookies of third-party services and analytics services:_

For the purpose of prompt delivery, higher-quality display and detailed analysis of the contents on the Website, the Company shall use the services which are the property of other third-party companies such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Google Inc., Gemius and others.

The companies mentioned as an example may use cookies on the user's device when he/she is working on the Website.

Please note that the Website may not have any effect on the operation of cookies used by these services. All the necessary information about their use can be found by visiting a relevant resource.

  * Google Analytics Terms of Service - <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/ru.html>
  * TNS Ukraine Privacy Policy is available at <https://tns-ua.com/konfidentsialnost>
  * Gemius Privacy Policy is available at <http://www.gemius.com.ua/politika-konfidencialnosti.html>
  * Bigmir Privacy and Personal Data Policy is available at <http://info.bigmir.net/privacy_policy>

_Cookie administration:_

Most popular web browsers (listed below) are configured to automatically accept cookies. To disable this feature, use the help function in your browser. Help can be accessed via the menu or using the F1 key.

Microsoft Edge - <https://privacy.microsoft.com/ru-ru/privacystatement>

Mozilla Firefox - <https://www.mozilla.org/ru/privacy/websites/#cookies>

Google Chrome - <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=ru>

Opera - <http://help.opera.com/Windows/11.50/ru/cookies.html>

Safari for macOS - <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US>

_Important:_

• web browsers of mobile devices may have a different configuration of cookie settings;

• please note that the fully-featured use of the Website is possible only when cookies are enabled;

• disabling of cookies may result in a restricted access to the contents and inappropriate functioning of the Website services.

To contact the Company about the use of cookies, please send an email to   

If the user does not enable the use of cookies or intentionally removes all cookies from his/her web browser, during his/her next visit to the Website the user shall again be offered to enable and use cookies.

 _ _User information obtained through cookies shall not be sold or publicly distributed, and shall be the property of the company which owns the resource.__

 **Website Interaction with Other Resources**

When the user uses the services, the Website pages may contain codes of other Internet resources and third parties, and as a consequence, these online resources and third parties receive your data. Therefore, these Internet resources can obtain and process the information that you have visited these pages, as well as other information transferred by the user's web browser. These Internet resources may be:

\- banner display system (e.g., DoubleClick for Publishers, Admixer AdRiver, etc.);

\- social networking plugins (e.g., Discus, Facebook, Twitter, Google+).

The Company needs to use the mentioned services for operational analysis of visits to the Website, internal and external evaluation of Website traffic, visit depth and user activity. The Company shall not store and shall not process the data obtained from these services.

Accordingly, if the user for some reason does not want these services to have access to his/her personal data, the user, at own discretion, may exit his/her account or profile and delete cookies (via his/her browser).

 **Security of Minors**

The Website is not intended for underage users. The Company is very serious about security issues, especially in respect of underage persons, therefore, on its part, the Company requests parents to explain their children the issues of security on the Internet, the specific purpose of such issues and the need to use certain services of the Website.

 **Interaction of the Company with Third Parties in Respect of Personal Data**

The Company shall not transfer personal data to third parties, except when such transfer is required by law, or at the request of the personal data subject, or in other cases set out in this Policy. The Company acknowledges that personal information is a valuable and integral content, including as a part of personal non-proprietary rights of any individual, therefore, the Company shall take all measures possible to protect personal information of the users which the latter voluntarily and knowingly transfer to the Company.

The Website may contain links to other websites (solely for information purposes). When a user links to such other websites, please note that this Policy shall not be applicable to such other websites. In this connection, the Company recommends that you review the privacy and personal data policy of each website before submitting any personal data which may identify you.

 **Privacy of the Personal Data Subject’s Activity on the Website**

Information about the Website activity (traffic) of the users passing through the network or user e -mail shall be protected in accordance with current law. This means that the Company shall in no way or manner breach the secrecy of the user’s activity when the latter uses the Website services.

 **Personal Data Protection**

The Company shall use generally accepted standards of technological and operational protection of information and personal data from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. However, despite all of the efforts, the Company may not guarantee absolute protection against any threat arising beyond the scope which the Company is able to regulate.

The Company shall ensure that all of the relevant confidentiality commitments are fulfilled, as well as technical and organizational security measures, in order to prevent an unauthorized or unlawful disclosure or processing of such information and data, their accidental loss, destruction or damage.

The Company shall provide access to information and personal data only to authorized employees who have agreed to maintain confidentiality of such information and data as required by the Company.

Dissemination of personal data without the consent of a relevant personal data subject or his/her authorized representative shall be allowed in cases prescribed by law and only (if necessary) for the sake of national security, economic welfare and human rights.

 **Terms of Personal Data Access**

The procedure of accessing third-party personal data shall be determined by the terms and conditions of the consent granted to the personal data holder in respect of such data processing, or in accordance with statutory requirements.

The user shall have the right to obtain any information about himself/herself from any subject of the relations arising in connection with personal data, subject to providing the last name, first and middle names, place of residence (place of stay) and details of the identification document of an individual submitting the request, except for cases established by law.

User's access to data about him/her shall be free of charge.

Access of a user to his/her personal data may not be delayed.

Access to third-party personal data may be delayed if the required data may not be provided within thirty calendar days after the date when a respective request is received. In such a case, the total period for resolving the issues addressed in the request may not exceed forty-five calendar days.

The notification about such a delay shall be communicated to the third party who submitted the request in writing and with clarification of the procedure of appeal against such a decision.

The decision about a delay of or refusal to provide access to personal data may be appealed against to the Human Rights Commissioner of the Verkhovna Rada of Ukraine or to a court of law.

 **Rights of the Personal Data Subject**

The Company hereby informs you about your rights as the personal data subject which are regulated by the Law of Ukraine "On Personal Data Protection", in particular, you shall have the following rights:

1) to know about the sources of collection and location of your personal data, the purpose of their processing, location or place of residence (place of stay) of the personal data holder or administrator, or to give a respective authorization to authorized persons of the latter to obtain such information, except for cases established by law;

2) to obtain information about the conditions of granting access to personal data, in particular, information about third parties to which your personal data are provided;

3) to have access to your personal data;

4) no later than thirty calendar days after the date on which a respective request is received, except for cases established by law, to receive the answer about whether your personal data are processed, and also to be informed of the contents of such personal data;

5) to submit a well-reasoned request to the personal data holder about your objection against processing of your personal data;

6) to submit a well-reasoned request about a change or destruction of your personal data by any holder and administrator of such personal data, if such data are processed illegally or are inaccurate;

7) to the protection of your personal data against any unlawful processing and accidental loss, destruction, or damage in connection with intentional concealment, failure to provide such data or their delayed provision, and also to be protected against provision of any information which is false or disgraces the honor, dignity and business reputation of an individual;

8) to submit complaints about processing of your personal data to the Human Rights Commissioner of the Verkhovna Rada of Ukraine or to a court of law;

9) to use legal remedies in case of any breach of the personal data protection laws;

10) to make warnings in respect of any restriction of the right to your personal data processing when granting your consent;

11) to withdraw your consent to personal data processing;

12) to be aware of the mechanism of automatic personal data processing;

13) to be protected against any automated decision having legal implications for you.

If you want to update, access, modify, block or delete your personal data, or to withdraw your consent to your personal data processing which you provided to the Company under this Policy, or if you have any comments, requests or complaints regarding your personal data processed by the Company, please contact the Company: by email at     or send an email to: 01001 Kyiv, Khreshchatyk 4 .

 **Policy Amendments**

From time to time and without a respective prior notice to the user, this Policy may be amended and supplemented, including in case of change of statutory requirements.

In case of any substantial change to this Policy, the Company shall publish a notification on the Website and specify the term during which such a change becomes effective. If within the specified term you do not refuse from accepting such a change in writing, this shall mean that you agree to the respective change to this Policy.

We kindly ask you from time to time to review our Policy to be duly aware of any changes or additions hereto.
